const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a feature of a life-threatening condition in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory rate > 25/min","bool":true},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Confusion","bool":false},{"option":"Silent chest","bool":false},{"option":"Bradycardia","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 24-year-old patient presents to the emergency room with acute exacerbation of asthma. He is tachycardic and is unable to complete a sentence in 1 breath. Oxygen therapy is given. What should be the next step in his management regimen?","answers":[{"option":"Intravenous fluids","bool":false},{"option":"Formoterol","bool":false},{"option":"Salmeterol","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium supplements","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Spirometry is being performed on a patient. The results show a reduced FEV1/FVC and an increased residual volume. Which of the following is the most likely cause?","answers":[{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Cystic fibrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following will not be a clinical finding in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Wheezing","bool":false},{"option":"Weight loss","bool":false},{"option":"Splenomegaly","bool":true},{"option":"Cough with sputum","bool":false},{"option":"Breathing through pursed lips","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which obstructive lung disease is characterized by a low diffusing capacity of the lung for carbon monoxide (DLCO)?","answers":[{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"T-helper 2 (TH2) cell's response in asthma recruits which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Erythrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":true},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which antibody is increased in atopic asthma?","answers":[{"option":"IgG","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":true},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Emphysema is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory scarring","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar damage","bool":true},{"option":"Permanent airway dilatation and scarring","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoconstriction","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Bronchiectasis is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammatory scarring","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Permanent airway dilatation","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar damage","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"'Eggshell' calcification in the hilar lymph nodes is a feature of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Berylliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Byssinosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true},{"option":"Anthracosis","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is a 5-lipoxygenase pathway inhibitor?","answers":[{"option":"Cromolyn","bool":false},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":true},{"option":"Monteluklast","bool":false},{"option":"Theophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Omalizumab","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a centrally acting antitussive?","answers":[{"option":"Opioids","bool":false},{"option":"Dextromethorphan","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocodone","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled steam","bool":true},{"option":"Codeine","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Postmortem lividity is fully established by how many hours after death?","answers":[{"option":"24-72 hours","bool":false},{"option":"6-8 hours","bool":true},{"option":"24 hours","bool":false},{"option":"3-6 hours","bool":false},{"option":"1-3 hours","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What kind of emphysema occurs in coal workers pneumoconiosis?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial","bool":false},{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false},{"option":"Paraseptal","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse","bool":false},{"option":"Centriacinar","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which chemotherapeutic agent may cause pulmonary fibrosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bleomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Paclitaxel","bool":false},{"option":"Vincristine","bool":false},{"option":"Cladribine","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclophosphamide","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Exposure to asbestos will not lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchogenic cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial fibrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which HLA haplotypes are involved in the development of sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"HLA-B7 and HLA-A1","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-B8 and HLA-A1","bool":true},{"option":"HLA-B38 and HLA-B8","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-B27 and HLA-B7","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-DRB1 and HLA-B8","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Chronic exposure to organic dust leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersensitivity pneumonitis","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"The radiograph of a 31-year-old patient shows bilateral reticulonodular opacities in the subpleural regions of the lower lobes. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common occupational lung disease?","answers":[{"option":"Farmer's lung","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":false},{"option":"Asymptomatic anthracosis","bool":false},{"option":"Progressive massive fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cancer that can metastasize to the lung?","answers":[{"option":"Breast cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Bone cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Liver cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Skin cancer","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the cause of panacinar emphysema?","answers":[{"option":"Past severe infection","bool":false},{"option":"Exposure to air pollutants","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Excessive smoking","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the major air pollutant of indoor smoke?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrogen dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Sulphur dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Radiation hazard most commonly leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Death due to chronic liver failure","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary artery diseases","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia only","bool":false},{"option":"Shortening of life always","bool":false},{"option":"Genetic changes and malformations","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Bronchiectasis is associated with which of the following syndromes?","answers":[{"option":"Broken heart syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Reye's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Turner's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Down syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Kartagener's syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 54-year-old man with obesity marks on his abdomen presents with dyspnea and chest pain. He has a history of paraneoplastic syndrome. After suitable investigations, the doctor diagnoses him with lung cancer. Which type of lung cancer is most likely present in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"How many gross stages are there in lobar pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"4","bool":true},{"option":"5","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":false},{"option":"6","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not associated with sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Arthralgia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":true},{"option":"Cranial nerve palsies","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac arrhythmias","bool":false},{"option":"Erythema nodosum","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the hematogenous dissemination of Mycobacterium tuberculosis called?","answers":[{"option":"Miliary tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculosis lymphadenitis","bool":false},{"option":"Potts disease","bool":false},{"option":"Primary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary tuberculosis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the causative organism of intestinal tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium avium-intracellulare","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium leprae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium bovis","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"First changes of tuberculosis occur in which region of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Throughout the lung","bool":false},{"option":"Middle lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Hilar lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Upper lobe","bool":false},{"option":"Lower lobe","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"In small cell carcinoma, 50-80% mutations are present in which of the following genes?","answers":[{"option":"EGFR","bool":false},{"option":"TTF1","bool":false},{"option":"TP53","bool":true},{"option":"Chromogranin","bool":false},{"option":"P/6","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not associated with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD)?","answers":[{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":false},{"option":"Depression","bool":false},{"option":"Muscle wasting","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic liver disease","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following histological findings will be observed in sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Caseating granuloma","bool":false},{"option":"Non-caseating granuloma","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bird-beak appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Coin lesions","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A medical student was studying a biopsy slide of a lung cancer patient. He found cells that were chromogranin positive. Which type of cancer is this?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchioloalveolar carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the most common type of bronchogenic tumor?","answers":[{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the most common causative organism of gram-negative nosocomial pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A forensic pathologist was working in his lab. On autopsy, he saw dilation and scarring of bronchi and bronchioles. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":true},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Brochiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A patient with tuberculosis develops bright orange-red-urine and calls his physician in panic. The patient has no other urinary tract symptoms. Which of the following medication is most likely to produce this side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":true},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 26-year-old housewife develops a high-grade fever, cough with purulent sputum, and pleuritic type of chest pain. The lady was previously in a good state of health. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute exacerbation of chronic bronchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 4-year-old boy has a 1-month history of recurrent cough with wheezing. There is no history of previous similar complaints and no family history of asthma or tuberculosis. Examination shows enlarged cervical nodes and bronchi. Chest X-Ray shows air trapping on the right side during inspiration. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Foreign body aspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Right middle lobe syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Nodal tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive airway disease","bool":false},{"option":"Gastro esophageal reflux","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought with complaints of difficulty in breathing, noisy harsh sounds produced during inspiration, and high-grade fever for 2 days. What will be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial tracheitis","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body inhalation","bool":false},{"option":"Laryngitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute laryngotracheobronchitis (croup)","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottitis","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 20-year-old thin, tall boy presented to the emergency room with sudden onset of cough, severe shortness of breath, and chest pain. He recently arrived from the USA after a 16-hour flight. Immediate chest X-Ray was advised with the suspicion of pneumothorax. Which chest examination finding best reveals pneumothorax?","answers":[{"option":"Increased breath sounds on auscultation on the affected side","bool":false},{"option":"Resonant percussion note on the affected side","bool":false},{"option":"Hyper-resonant percussion note on the affected side","bool":true},{"option":"Dull percussion note on the affected side","bool":false},{"option":"Increased chest movements on the affected side","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 28-year-old female came with acute shortness of breath for one day. She is experiencing night symptoms for the past 2 months. What is the cause of raised diffusion capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO) in pulmonary function tests?","answers":[{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Obstructive sleep apnea","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac failure","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"An elderly female is admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU) for acute respiratory distress syndrome on the 4th day of total hip replacement for a fracture of the neck of the femur. Which of the following is the cause of acute respiratory distress syndrome in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboembolism","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Malignant mesothelioma is associated with exposure to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Arsenic","bool":false},{"option":"Lead","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":true},{"option":"Copper dust","bool":false},{"option":"Silica","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Inhaled salbutamol is useful in bronchial asthma due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Suppresses hyper-reactivity","bool":false},{"option":"Round the clock prophylaxis of asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Reduces inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Status asthmaticus","bool":false},{"option":"Aborting/terminating asthma attacks","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Rifampin is not indicated in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus osteomyelitis","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Plaque","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most serious adverse event associated with ethambutol?","answers":[{"option":"Psychotic reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Optic neuritis","bool":true},{"option":"Nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow suppression","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of these is a life-saving drug given parenterally in severe status asthmaticus that will act by inhibiting phospholipase A2?","answers":[{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false},{"option":"Prednisone","bool":true},{"option":"Aminophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"The type of asphyxia that is associated with anesthesia and surgical maneuvers is termed as:","answers":[{"option":"Pathological asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Iatrogenic asphyxia","bool":true},{"option":"Mechanical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic asphyxia","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true about pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"It is an infectious disease","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilators are drug of choice for treatment","bool":true},{"option":"There is recently developed x-ray shadowing","bool":false},{"option":"It is an acute respiratory illness","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion is a complication","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the most common cause of lung abscess?","answers":[{"option":"Antecedent primary lung infection","bool":false},{"option":"Aspiration of infective material","bool":true},{"option":"Neoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Septic embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A body has been found hanging from a tree. The ligature mark runs obliquely on the neck and ecchymosis adjacent to the ligature mark on the neck muscle is found. This is the feature of:","answers":[{"option":"Strangulation","bool":false},{"option":"Postmortem hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Ante-mortem hanging","bool":true},{"option":"Burking","bool":false},{"option":"Garroting","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Mycobacteria do not get stained properly because of their high content of:","answers":[{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Carbohydrates","bool":false},{"option":"Lipids","bool":true},{"option":"Mannose","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"In a putrefied body death resulted from drowning, diatoms are found in which of the following organs/viscera?","answers":[{"option":"Gall bladder and liver","bool":false},{"option":"Hilum of right lung and right ear","bool":false},{"option":"Stomach and left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Ileum and under surface of liver","bool":false},{"option":"Brain and bone marrow","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A neck infection in front of prevertebral fascia may extend:","answers":[{"option":"Into inferior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Through superior into posterior mediastinum","bool":true},{"option":"Into middle mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Into superior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Through superior into anterior mediastinum","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A patient with tuberculosis is started on isoniazid (INH) as part of a multidrug regimen. The physician also starts therapy with vitamin B6 at the same time. Which of the following is the main reason for giving the vitamin B6 prophylactically?","answers":[{"option":"Facilitates INH renal excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents some adverse effects of INH therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Is a cofactor required for activation of INH","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibits metabolism of INH","bool":false},{"option":"Potentiates the antitubercular activity of the INH","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"The human organ which was first examined by nuclear medicine studies was:","answers":[{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid","bool":true},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 55-year-old patient suffering from persistent dry cough for the last 2-months due to unknown reasons wants to get a drug without having constipating effects. Which of the following would you prescribe?","answers":[{"option":"Physostigmine","bool":false},{"option":"Codeine","bool":false},{"option":"Pholcodine","bool":false},{"option":"Dextromethorphan","bool":true},{"option":"Hydrocodone","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which HLA subtype is involved in the development of sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"HLA-A3","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-B8","bool":true},{"option":"HLA-A2","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-B27","bool":false},{"option":"HLA-B1","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following anti-asthmatic drugs is not given by inhalation?","answers":[{"option":"Tiotropium","bool":false},{"option":"Doxophylline","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Theophylline","bool":true},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the most likely cause of death by drowning in freshwater?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Lung ballooning","bool":false},{"option":"Convulsions","bool":false},{"option":"Atrial fibrillation","bool":false},{"option":"Ventricular fibrillation","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which one of the following is a prophylactic agent used in cases of bronchial asthma that stabilizes mast cells?","answers":[{"option":"Terbutaline","bool":false},{"option":"Cromolyn","bool":true},{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false},{"option":"Ipratropium bromide","bool":false},{"option":"Aminophylline","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a criterion for clinical diagnosis of death?","answers":[{"option":"Absence of pulse","bool":false},{"option":"Absence of breathing","bool":false},{"option":"A flat electroencephalogram (EEG)","bool":true},{"option":"Fixed dilated pupils","bool":false},{"option":"A loss of brainstem reflexes","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"There is no limit of exhumation in which of the following countries?","answers":[{"option":"France","bool":false},{"option":"Pakistan","bool":true},{"option":"Germany","bool":false},{"option":"England","bool":false},{"option":"Australia","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"When does rigor mortis appear in case of hanging?","answers":[{"option":"Appears late and long duration","bool":true},{"option":"Appears early and long duration","bool":false},{"option":"Appears early and short duration","bool":false},{"option":"Slowly appears and long duration","bool":false},{"option":"Slowly appears and short duration","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is a sure sign of death by drowning?","answers":[{"option":"Postmortem lividity","bool":false},{"option":"Clenched fists","bool":false},{"option":"Froth from mouth","bool":true},{"option":"Distended lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Cadeveric spasms","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the approximate brain weight of an adult human?","answers":[{"option":"1.0 kg","bool":false},{"option":"2.0 kg","bool":false},{"option":"1.3 kg","bool":false},{"option":"1.5 kg","bool":true},{"option":"2.2 kg","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the most probable cause of death in a judicial hanging?","answers":[{"option":"Choking","bool":false},{"option":"Neck fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Skull fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Strangulation","bool":false},{"option":"Asphyxiation","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the medical term for the yellow, creamy pus in the pleural cavity?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural exudate","bool":false},{"option":"Pustule","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural transudate","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Empyema","bool":true}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Pulmonary edema does not occur in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Adverse reaction to certain medications","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Breast cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Burns","bool":false},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which type of infarction is seen in pulmonary infarcts?","answers":[{"option":"Coagulative","bool":false},{"option":"White","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhagic","bool":true},{"option":"Gangrenous","bool":false},{"option":"Ischemic","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most important air pollutant of the greenhouse effect?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitric oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrogen sulphide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":true}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis can be cultured in which medium?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcuseosin methylene blue (EMB)","bool":false},{"option":"Blood agar","bool":false},{"option":"None of the above","bool":false},{"option":"Löwenstein–Jensen","bool":true},{"option":"Chocolate agar","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What stain is used for Mycobacterium tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hematoxylin and eosin stain","bool":false},{"option":"Congo red capsule stain","bool":false},{"option":"Ziehl–Neelsen stain","bool":true},{"option":"Endospore stain","bool":false},{"option":"Gram-negative stain","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Pneumothorax is most commonly associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"The neck of a person was impacted by 15 kgs of weight. What is the most likely cause of death?","answers":[{"option":"Asphyxiation","bool":true},{"option":"Throttling","bool":false},{"option":"Choking","bool":false},{"option":"Neck fracture","bool":false},{"option":"Strangulation","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect about asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Reversible disease","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Communicable disease","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Airway hyperreactivity","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common type of emphysema?","answers":[{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false},{"option":"Paraseptal","bool":false},{"option":"Centrilobular","bool":true},{"option":"Proximal acinar","bool":false},{"option":"Distal acinar","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which type of emphysema involves proximal airway damage?","answers":[{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Paraseptal","bool":false},{"option":"Distal acinar","bool":false},{"option":"Centrilobular","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which one of the following is an external sign of antemortem hanging in case of instantaneous death?","answers":[{"option":"Hemorrhages in the lymph nodes above the ligature mark","bool":false},{"option":"Congestion in the lymph nodes above and below ligature mark","bool":false},{"option":"Face and head above ligature may be congested","bool":false},{"option":"Bruising, rupture, or laceration of neck's soft structures","bool":false},{"option":"Tongue protruding with saliva dribbling from the mouth","bool":true}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the most common causative organism of community-acquired pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the correct Light's criteria for LDH serum ratio in exudative pleural effusion?","answers":[{"option":"Greater than 0.6 IU/ml","bool":true},{"option":"Greater than 0.5 IU/ml","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 0.5 IU/ml","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 0.6 IU/ml","bool":false},{"option":"Less than 0.4 IU/ml","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common causative organism of pneumonia caused due to faulty air conditioning?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Albuterol is known to cause bronchial relaxation by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Accumulation of IP3","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of cytosolic calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of neurotransmitter acetylcholine","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of cGMP","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of cAMP","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the mechanism of action of sodium cromolyn in asthma patients?","answers":[{"option":"Cytokine inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Selective beta-2 agonist","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cell stabilizer","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchodilator","bool":false},{"option":"Leukotriene inhibitor","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which enzyme does albuterol influence during its mechanism of action?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Protein cyclase","bool":false},{"option":"Glutaminyl cyclase","bool":false},{"option":"Adenylyl cyclase","bool":true},{"option":"Guanylyl cyclase","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which type of pneumonia is seen in patients that have a weakened immune system due to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV)?","answers":[{"option":"Interstitial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Aspiration pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchopneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Lobar pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic feature used to diagnose croup?","answers":[{"option":"Whooping cough","bool":false},{"option":"Barking cough","bool":true},{"option":"Productive cough","bool":false},{"option":"Dry cough","bool":false},{"option":"Post-viral cough","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is a long-acting beta-agonist used for the treatment of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Salmeterol","bool":true},{"option":"Zafirlukast","bool":false},{"option":"Theophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Montelukast","bool":false},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of action of aspirin?","answers":[{"option":"Increased mast cell activity","bool":false},{"option":"Promotion of cyclooxygenase pathway","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of mast cell activity","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilation","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of cyclooxygenase pathway","bool":true}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs has both antihistamine and mast cell stabilizing properties?","answers":[{"option":"Mometasone","bool":false},{"option":"Fluticasone","bool":false},{"option":"Beclomethasone","bool":false},{"option":"Montelukast","bool":false},{"option":"Ketotifen","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What can a saddle embolus lead to?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Nose bleed","bool":false},{"option":"Sudden death","bool":true},{"option":"Chest pain","bool":false},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is an antifolate drug?","answers":[{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false},{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":true},{"option":"Amodiaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Halofantrine","bool":false},{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is an inhaled corticosteroid prescribed for the treatment of asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Methylprednisolone","bool":false},{"option":"Beclomethasone","bool":true},{"option":"Dexamethasone","bool":false},{"option":"Prednisone","bool":false},{"option":"Triamcinolone","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is a mast cell stabilizer?","answers":[{"option":"Diphenhydramine","bool":false},{"option":"Loratadine","bool":false},{"option":"Cromoglicic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Chlorpheniramine","bool":false},{"option":"Clemastine","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs can lead to vestibular toxicity as an adverse effect?","answers":[{"option":"Doxycycline","bool":false},{"option":"Amoxicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Cephalexin","bool":false},{"option":"Ciprofloxacin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs acts as a mucolytic agent?","answers":[{"option":"Tramadol","bool":false},{"option":"Acetaminophen","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcysteine","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylsalicylic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Oxycodone","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following drugs is used in isolated therapy for uncomplicated tuberculosis (TB)?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":true},{"option":"Bedaquiline","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following lung cancers arises from neurosecretory cells?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchioalveolar carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of these is the most common type of lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Small cell carninoma","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Hemoptysis is commonly seen in which type of lung cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchioalveolar carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries is most commonly blocked in autopsy in case of coronary atherosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"Left subclavian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Right marginal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Left anterior descending artery","bool":true},{"option":"Right coronary artery","bool":false},{"option":"Circumflex artery","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"The gene most often altered in squamous cell cancers is which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"NSCLC","bool":false},{"option":"KRAS","bool":false},{"option":"TP58","bool":false},{"option":"EGFR","bool":false},{"option":"TP53","bool":true}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which is the most common lung cancer seen in women?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchioalveolar carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which lung carcinoma is related to the adrenocorticotrophic hormone (ACTH)?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bionchioalveolar carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following organisms most commonly causes atypical pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 20-year-old man comes to the outpatient clinic with a complaint of flu-like symptoms. He is diagnosed with pneumonia, showing bilateral lung infiltrates. What is the causative organism in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 25-year-old man suffering from a respiratory illness is advised by the doctor to get a chest X-ray. There are pleural plaques seen on his x-ray. These plaques are indicative of which disease?","answers":[{"option":"Asbestosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"In which of the following diseases fibrosis on lung CT is initially seen in subpleural patches, but eventually results in diffuse fibrosis with end-stage 'honeycomb' lung?","answers":[{"option":"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumoconioses","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersensitivity pneumonitis","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Hypersensitivity pneumonitis can be caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cigarette smoke","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Perfume vapours","bool":false},{"option":"Animal droppings","bool":false},{"option":"Organic dust","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"While reading an x-ray, a doctor observes eggshell calcifications in the lungs. This condition is caused by exposure to which of the following agents?","answers":[{"option":"Cigarette smoke","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":false},{"option":"Alcohol","bool":false},{"option":"Organic dust","bool":false},{"option":"Silica","bool":true}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following conditions is most likely to cause sudden death?","answers":[{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary thrombus","bool":false},{"option":"Saddle embolus","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A patient's pulmonary function test shows FEVI/FVC > 0.7 and FEV1 100% of predicted with decreased total lung capacity (TLC). Which of the following patterns is this?","answers":[{"option":"Non-specific reductions in FEVI and FVC","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Normal pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive pattern","bool":true}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 27-year-old patient got a chest X-ray which showed a round thick-walled cavity with an air-fluid level, and surrounding consolidation. Which of the following is the most likely cause of this patient's condition?","answers":[{"option":"Foreign body inhalation","bool":false},{"option":"Antecedent infection","bool":false},{"option":"Lung infection","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false},{"option":"Aspiration pneumonia","bool":true}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not associated with triggering or increasing the risk of developing asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Formula feeding instead of breastmilk","bool":false},{"option":"Low population density","bool":true},{"option":"Parental asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Childhood respiratory syncytial virus infection","bool":false},{"option":"Childhood tuberculosis infection","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is a triggering factor for asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Childhood respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) infection","bool":true},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"The predominance of lactobacilli in the gut","bool":false},{"option":"Childhood infection with parasites","bool":false},{"option":"Living on farm","bool":false}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Why is a 'Y' shaped incision made during an autopsy?","answers":[{"option":"To study the abdominal structures","bool":false},{"option":"To gain access to pelvic structures","bool":false},{"option":"To perform a lung dissection","bool":false},{"option":"To perform a heart dissection","bool":false},{"option":"To allow maximum approach to neck structures","bool":true}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is an example of pericellular histotoxic type of asphyxia?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon monoxide poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Opiates poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac arrest","bool":false},{"option":"Chloroform poisoning","bool":true},{"option":"Cyanide poisoning","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Despite a thorough postmortem physical examination, chemical analysis, and microscopic examination, sometimes the cause of death cannot be arrived at. What is this called?","answers":[{"option":"Hidden autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Unknown autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Negative autopsy","bool":true},{"option":"False autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Positive autopsy","bool":false}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following organs is not dissected in detail during autopsy?","answers":[{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Spinal cord","bool":true},{"option":"Lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which bones help in determining the sex of an individual?","answers":[{"option":"Femur","bool":false},{"option":"Skull and femur","bool":false},{"option":"Mandible and femur","bool":false},{"option":"Skull and pelvis","bool":true},{"option":"Pelvis","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Where is the incision for an autopsy of the head made?","answers":[{"option":"From one temple to the other temple till the occipital notch","bool":false},{"option":"From one mastoid to the other mastoid till the base of skull","bool":false},{"option":"The location of the incision does not matter","bool":false},{"option":"From one temple to the other temple till the base of skull","bool":false},{"option":"From one mastoid to the other mastoid till the occipital notch","bool":true}]},{"id":124,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following radiological methods is the best way to diagnose desquamative interstitial pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging","bool":false},{"option":"Chest x-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Fluoroscopy","bool":false},{"option":"High-resolution computed tomography (HRCT)","bool":true},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following best describes the radiological findings in the case of desquamative interstitial pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Scattered, patchy consolidation","bool":false},{"option":"Multifocal consolidation","bool":false},{"option":"Honeycomb-like appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse interstitial infiltrates","bool":true}]},{"id":126,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Why is pyridoxine given in combination with isoniazid?","answers":[{"option":"Because both of these have the same therapeutic effect","bool":false},{"option":"To reduce its bioavailability","bool":false},{"option":"To increase its bioavailability","bool":false},{"option":"To potentiate the drug","bool":false},{"option":"To avoid side effects","bool":true}]},{"id":127,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following are rarely given to asthma patients?","answers":[{"option":"Leukotriene modifiers","bool":false},{"option":"Oral corticosteroids","bool":true},{"option":"Long-acting β-agonists (LABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Short-acting β-agonists (SABA)","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled corticosteroids","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not given for productive cough?","answers":[{"option":"Dextromethorphan","bool":true},{"option":"Acetylcysteine","bool":false},{"option":"Vasaka","bool":false},{"option":"Guaiacol","bool":false},{"option":"Bromhexine","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 16-year-old boy develops fever with chills and a productive cough. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Nosocomial pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Health care associated pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Community-acquired pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchopneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 31-year-old patient who is immunocompromised due to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) will develop pneumonia caused by which of the following organisms?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumocystis carinii","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":false},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought with complaints of difficulty in breathing, noisy harsh sounds produced during inspiration, and high-grade fever for 2 days.  What will be the finding on his chest X-ray?","answers":[{"option":"Collar's sign","bool":false},{"option":"Continuous diaphragm sign","bool":false},{"option":"Cottage loaf sign","bool":false},{"option":"Steeple sign","bool":false},{"option":"Thumbprinting sign","bool":true}]},{"id":132,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought with complaints of difficulty in breathing, noisy harsh sounds produced during inspiration, and high-grade fever for 2 days. What will be the most important step in management?","answers":[{"option":"Racemic epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":true},{"option":"Hydration","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous dextrose","bool":false},{"option":"Intravenous normal saline","bool":false}]},{"id":133,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought with complaints of difficulty in breathing, noisy harsh sounds produced during inspiration, and high-grade fever for 2 days. Which of the following is the most likely causative organism causing this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus viridans","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenza type a","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus influenza type b","bool":true}]},{"id":134,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of these screening tests is most commonly used to diagnose tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Polymerase chain reaction (PCR)","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Sputum culture test","bool":false},{"option":"Tuberculin skin test","bool":true},{"option":"Bacilus Calmette-Guerin (BCG)","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is a centrally acting antitussive?","answers":[{"option":"Prenoxdiazine","bool":false},{"option":"Bromhexine","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium iodide","bool":false},{"option":"Acetylcysteine","bool":false},{"option":"Noscapine","bool":true}]},{"id":136,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A pregnant woman has severe asthma. She neglects her treatment by not taking her inhaled corticosteroids. Which of the following is most likely to happen?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Severe cardiac problems","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Growth retardation","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal eclampsia","bool":true}]},{"id":137,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"How does the volume of dead space change with age?","answers":[{"option":"Marked increase","bool":false},{"option":"No change","bool":false},{"option":"Increaes slightly","bool":true},{"option":"Marked reduction","bool":false},{"option":"Reduces slightly","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is not included in the diagnostic criteria of pulmonary hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary vascular resistance > 240 dynes/s/cm(-5)","bool":false},{"option":"Mean pulmonary artery pressure > 30 mmHg with exercise","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary capillary wedge pressure < 15mmHg","bool":false},{"option":"Mean pulmonary artery pressure > 30 mmHg at rest","bool":true},{"option":"Mean pulmonary artery pressure > 25 mmHg at rest","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding bronchial carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Endobronchial stents are used for pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Radiotherapy is given to alleviate bone pain in primary lung cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Chemotherapy side-effects can be treated with 5-HT3 receptor agonists","bool":false},{"option":"The overall prognosis in bronchial carcinoma is good","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoscopic laser treatment is not useful","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 24-year-old patient with asthma has a peak expiratory flow (PEF) of 25%, FEV1 (predicted > 80%), with diurnal asthma episodes greater than 2 per week, and nocturnal episodes greater than 2 per month. He is currently on beta-agonists and inhaled corticosteroids (ICS). Which type of asthma is he suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Severe nocturnal asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Mild intermittent asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Severe persistent asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Mild persistent asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Moderate persistent asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 41-year-old man with a history of hypoglycemia goes to the doctor for a routine check. A chest X-ray shows an abnormal mass attached by a pedicle. What is the most likely condition?","answers":[{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant mesothelioma","bool":false},{"option":"Abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Solitary fibrous nodule","bool":true}]},{"id":142,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A man has been working at a silica factory for the last 15 years. He develops tuberculosis. Inhibition of which of the following cell line in his lungs made him more susceptible to developing tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Why is dextromethorphan an antitussive drug?","answers":[{"option":"It increases the threshold for cough","bool":true},{"option":"It is an NMDA receptor agonist","bool":false},{"option":"It increases the intensity of dry cough","bool":false},{"option":"It reduces productive cough","bool":false},{"option":"It inhibits the activity of cilia","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following is a folate antagonist?","answers":[{"option":"Primaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Amodiaquine","bool":false},{"option":"Halofantrine","bool":false},{"option":"Para-aminosalicylic acid (PAS)","bool":true},{"option":"Chloroquine","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A physician prescribed an anti-tuberculosis drug to a patient. He started feeling a tingling sensation. What could you give to reverse this effect?","answers":[{"option":"Folate","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin C","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B6","bool":true}]},{"id":146,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Surgical intervention is required in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mild persistent asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bullous emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Severe asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"Which of the following types of hanging is suspected in the setting of a male lying naked on the bed in a pornographic setting?","answers":[{"option":"Lynching","bool":false},{"option":"Autoerotic hanging","bool":true},{"option":"Accidental hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Judicial hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Homicidal hanging","bool":false}]},{"id":148,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"What is the antidote for phenol?","answers":[{"option":"Ethanol","bool":false},{"option":"Lime water","bool":false},{"option":"Castor oil","bool":true},{"option":"Milk of magnesia","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium bicarbonate","bool":false}]},{"id":149,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2019","question":"A 20-year-old male presents to the clinic with the complaint of fever for 5 days. Chest examination reveals dull percussion notes and decreased breath sounds in the left lung base. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Lung collapse","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]}]
export default arr